In our next clip we're going to discuss and I'm going to show you some steps, on trying to move in half a step.
Everything I like to do in boxing, I like to tell my boxers, is to try to do it in just a half a step increment.
Half a step with one foot, half a step with the other.
If you take a full step with one foot and then a half a step with the other, you're still too far spread apart.
Your heels should be shoulder-width apart, no less, and only more when you're advancing, okay?
So whether you're going to the side, or whether you're going backwards, or whether you're going to the other side, or whether you're going forward, try to do everything in little half a steps.
Half a step with one foot, follow it with a half a step with the other foot.
You're going to be less predictable that way.
You're going to get less tired that way.
Everything done in half steps.